¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions

{CAESER_IN_GAUL_TITLE}Caesar in Gaul

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Rise of Persia campaign
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DESCR}The year is 559 B.C, and four great empires divide the known world. The Medes, with their mighty empire, have expanded their frontiers from the Far East all the way to Asia Minor. The Lydians, with their rich empire, dominate almost all of Asia Minor and may soon expand even further. Egyptians, controlling a long lasting empire, gain wealth in their regions stretching from Syria to the north, and Aithiopia to the south. Babylonians, with their unrivaled, fabulously rich city of Babylon, which they call Bâb-Ilû, gain wealth and expand their territories, dominating all of Mesopotamia. Kingdoms and empires fight for total domination to rule the world. One nation is about to change the fate of the world forever.......\n\n
In the region of Parsa, a small kingdom is soon going to rise to become an empire...perhaps the greatest empire the world will ever see. In Aryanam, King Kuruš, known as Kyros to the Greeks, II has become king of the Persians, has united the separate clans, but still remains under rule of the Medes. Soon, however, this will all change; as he has plans do crush the Medes, siege Babylon, and destroy the Lydians... Persia is ready for to sprout from its seed, starting a new period in history...  This won't be easy, as many kingdoms and empires await him and his armies.\n\n
The warrior caste of Magadha, coming from the far east of India, will soon sweep across the west and claim Asia as hers. To the north, nomad tribes will invade from the Steppes, swiftly marching into Persian land. To the far west, to Hellas, small Greek states fight for the control of Greece and then to extend their civilization all the way to Persia… Who will forge the greatest empire?

{SONS_OF_MARS_KYRENE_TITLE}The House Of Julii
{SONS_OF_MARS_KYRENE_DESCR}You are the new leader (pater familias) of a young and upcoming noble (Patrician) family.\n\n
You have been given a military command by the Senate and People of Rome (SPQR) and must help forge a safe, strong and lasting empire in Italy.\n\n
Your first objectives are to repel a barbarian attack, just near Rome, and then move to take control of the town of Tarquinii, to the north west of Rome.\n\n
As your tutor will have told you, It is up to you to "seize the day" (carpe diem). 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GREEK_CITIES_TITLE}Lakedaimon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GREEK_CITIES_DESCR}Difficulty: Moderately Hard\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nUn-walled Sparta... home to legend and stories of the greatest heroism. The finest hoplites in the entire world train together day and night, living for battle. Striving to conquer their neighbors to support their unorthodox regime the Lakedaimonioi lust for new lands cannot be quashed easily. The Messenioi have fallen and become helot slaves to the Lakedaimonioi. With them preparing for war almost constantly it could only be a matter of time before all Greece is held under her hegemony.\n\n
Lakedaimon's mainstay of battle is the Spartiatai - The most formidable hoplites to ever grasp a spear stand unflinchingly in the face of any danger. The Krypteia , masters of the night, might infiltrate the enemy camps and wreak havoc among the terrified victims. Their cavalry is limited, but the Lakedaimonioi need no prissy horsemen to win their battles. All they need is a strong right arm and the will to stand and fight!
\n\nTheir lands are mountainous and not suitable for much agriculture which forces the Lakedaimonioi to expand and conquer new richer territories. With Athens only a few stadia away an explosive war is soon to erupt and only the most cunning of commanders will be able to come out on top. With Greece being desperately fought over the armies of the east may soon take their chance to strike at the vulnerable Hellenes. The Lakedaimonioi no doubt will be there to raise an iron-tipped spear and stand for the freedom and glory of Greece!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KYRENE_TITLE}Kyrene
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KYRENE_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nGreek settlers longing for a new hope at distant shores landed and in northern Libya founding the city of Kyrene,  a name soon to be well known in Africa. At first having good relationships with the Libyan indigenous population, the Greeks soon violated them, expelled them from their lands with the help of their superior weapons. Further expeditions were started and finally the Libyans managed to stir up the mighty Pharaoh for a fight against the expanding city state, but even he lost against the proud Greek phalanx.\nHowever, no one is invincible and the citizens had to pay a terrible price for that lesson when thousands of their sons never returned from yet another expedition against the Libyans. Now they concentrate on economical strength, but that power can be easily translated into military power...\n\n
The excellent economical basis of the state ensured rich and effective equipment for the typical Greek hoplites also let into battle by the Kings of Kyrene. Adapting, they chose to use even Egyptian techniques for their arms and armor. Also Egyptian influence is reflecting in their lifestyle, especially the religion seeing the absorption of the oracle god Amun as Zeus Ammon. Still, trade is the best source of income since Kyrene holds the iron monopoly on the mysterious Silphion-plant.\n\n
The King of Kyrene has three different choices if he wants to expand further. In the south, there are the ferocious Libyans with their poor land, in the east, the mighty Pharaoh awaits, more than ready to crush Kyrene, but there is still another option, a naval expedition, to conquer many distant lands. 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DACIA_TITLE}Taras
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DACIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe polis of Taras looms high and proud over the western Greek states. Like the other Greek colonies it was founded during a period of great land hunger in Mainland Greece, Taras is the most powerful of the city states that migrated westwards to southern Italy. Whilst leaving their homeland behind the men of Taras retained their Greek culture and there are strong ties between the colonies and their mother states.\n\n
They, like their homeland brethren, have a strong hoplite tradition steeped in experience and training. The Western hoplites are every bit as powerful as their mainland counterparts. However the men of Taras are still most capable horsemen incorporating Italian influences, as such the cavalry of Taras is a formidable force more powerful than the average commander expects of Greek cavalry.\n\n
Taras is situated in a perfect position to reap the benefits of the many trade routes passing through the Mediterranean. In this way they can supply vast fleets and armies to subdue the northern barbarians and also be ready to mount an invasion towards the east. Being that they are isolated from most nations the men of Taras will have much time to build up their forces and rampage through whichever territory they choose! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SELEUCID_TITLE}Athenaioi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SELEUCID_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe Democracy, which made Athenai (Athens) famous has not yet come to pass, Athenai is ruled by one man Peisistratos, son of Hippokrates. Solon the Law giver has recently died and the poor people of Athenai have lost their benefactor. But the recent war with Megara has left the Athenaioi in need of a strong leader and Peisistratos is that man, with the drive to succeed and a strong army at his back it is only a matter of time before Greece is unified under an empire with dominating Athenaioi. Athenai has yet to come into her golden age, but it is only a matter of time before Athenai bursts into her prime and creates a legacy that will last through the ages.\n\n 
The army of the Athenaioi is not a strong cavalry force, neither do they possess masterful archers, but Athenai's infantry is a master of the phalanx and certainly a force to be reckoned with. A charge from the phalanx can tear through almost any infantry, this wall of bronze is an unstoppable force when engaged head on, however, a skilled commander will always keep a reserve to stop his valued phalanx from being flanked. The troops are drawn from the citizens of Athenai, each man fighting with what he can afford but all of them fighting for their city. It is this strong belief that the citizens are part of the city that gives the Athenaioi such courage in battle, and in defense of Athenai it would be hard to find a man who fled rather than fight for his stake in the city.\n\n 
Athenai will soon be on the lips of every Easterner fearing Greek as the valiant defenders of Greece who played David to the Great King's Goliath. But for now Athenai will build up her forces and exert the power she is destined to have over the Hellenic world.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Ionia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Difficulty: Moderately Hard\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nWhen the land hunger of the mainland Greeks grew too much to bear they sent out many citizens to found new cities and colonies all over the Mediterranean. Many of these colonies were founded in Asia Minor on the fringes of the world’s greatest empires. Unfortunately for the Iones they are continually beset by mighty kings demanding tribute and service. But this is not the path for a proud Greek! The Iones can utilize their massive cities to draw on armies ready to face the haughty barbarians.\n\n
The Iones, like all Greeks, heavily rely on hoplites. But hoplites are the sort of infantry to get the job done no matter what the odds, and it is odds that the Iones are going up against. Lydia to the north, Media and Babylon to the east whilst Egypt lurks in the south leaves the Iones in a tight spot. Only a skillful commander will be able to beat back the barbarians and establish Greek supremacy in the east as well as the west!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MACEDON_TITLE}Makedon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MACEDON_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nThe Makedonoi are not major players on the world stage, nor are they the home to the powerful armies that might one day rule the world. They live a peaceful life in northern Greece with only minimal conflict with the barbaric Thrakians. To maintain their independence and prosper, will be a severely tough challenge for any commander in this critical stage of history. The Makedones army of sheep could do spectacularly well if led by the right Lion.\n\n
Situated in northern Greece the Makedones have ample land for agriculture and the practice of horsemanship. With strong ties to the nobles in Thessaly, they can train horsemen alongside some of the best in Greece. They do not form a solid battle lines of a phalanx with the same strength and skill of their southern Hellenic counter parts, but with a stronger cavalry the Makedones could adapt to disrupt the enemy and snatch victory.\n\n
The armies of all the major empires are coming together for one great clash of arms; can Makedonia ride the storm and survive independent? Or better still subdue their haughty neighbors and reign supreme in the west! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THRACE_TITLE}Bessoi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THRACE_DESCR}Difficulty: Moderately Medium\nConquest Type: Choice\nYou can choose whether to train either your own or local troops in conquered regions\n\nThe Thrakian Bessoi are a tribe with the reputation of being wild and savage even among the wild and savage Thrakian tribes that inhabit the region north of Hellas. Sharing only minimal cultural ties with their southern brethren the Thrakians are rightly feared for their ferocity and impetuous nature. Occasionally raiding into parts of Makedonia and fending off raids from the Skudata are the most organized of the Bessoi international politics. But usually the Thrakian tribes fight each other more than any unified enemy. But with a strong chieftain able to manipulate the will of these terrifying warriors, the Bessoi could bond the tribes into a most fearsome fighting machine.\n\n
Their lands are brutal and unforgiving to the Greeks in the south. But the Bessoi battle the elements for survival and it has made them a hardy people. The lack of resources in the area forces the Thrakians to raid Northern Greece for booty and slaves. This forced conflict will soon brew into bloody wars with first Makedon and maybe further into the more powerful city states of Greece. The Thrakian war machine consists of fierce warriors willing to sacrifice their lives for pure blood lust. With most nimble but deadly men the Thrakians formed the archetype of the peltast while the nobles support all their actions. A perfect combination for the thick Thrakian woods\n\n
With the Skudata constantly raiding their provinces the Bessoi will need to find new resources quickly to build up armies to halt their advances. When the Bessoi have secured their kingdom and found their target, the rest of the world will learn to tremble at the news that the Thrakians are coming for their homes! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERMANS_TITLE}Autariatai
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERMANS_DESCR}Difficulty: Moderately Medium\nConquest Type: Choice\nYou can choose whether to train either your own or local troops in conquered regions\n\nThe Autariatae or Autariatai (alternatively, Autariates; Ancient Greek: Αὐταριᾶται, Autariatai; Latin: Autariatae) were an Illyrian people that lived between the valleys of the Lim and the Tara, beyond the Accursed Mountains, and the valley of West Morava. Their territory was located inland from the Ardiaei and the Lake Skodra, extending east to the Dardani and north or northeast to the Triballi.\n\nAlong with the Ardiaei and the Dardani, the Autariatae are mentioned by Strabo in his Geographica as one of the three strongest Illyrian peoples in the pre-Roman Balkans. Following defeat during the Celtic invasions of the Balkans in the 4th century, a part of the Autariatae who remained in Bosnia adopted Celtic culture later in their history. Another part moved southwards and after an agreement with the Kingdom of Macedonia, 20,000 settled in the Parorbelian mountain range, in the borderlands between modern southeastern North Macedonia, northern Greece and southwestern Bulgaria.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCYTHIA_TITLE}Skudata
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCYTHIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe Skudata, known as Skythai (Scythians) by the Greeks, lived an isolated life away from the troubles of the urbanized world, with a simple herdsman's life the nomad makes a living with his animals. Having only to move with them like one of the herd and take them to the favored grazing spots leaves much time for the practice of horsemanship and shooting the bow. A nomad’s life may seem simple to the rest of the world, but living in such harsh climates and travelling a great many miles a day on the steppes every day has made the Skudata a fierce enemy. Whilst ordinarily the Skudata are not bothered by the politics of distant nations with their cities and decadence, the time always comes around when the nomads must mount their warhorses, take up the spear and bow and raid the neighboring countries for gold, cattle and glory.\n\n
The Skudata formed a loose network of nomadic tribes of horse-riding herdsmen and raiders. They invaded many areas in the steppes of Eurasia, including areas in present-day Kazakhstan, Azerbaijan and southern Russia. Ruled by small, closely-allied elites, the Skudata had a reputation for their skilled archers, and many gained employment as mercenaries. But the Skudata's main strength lies in their much practiced art of horse-archery and furthermore their developed use of heavily armoured cavalry. The Skudata cavalry has a great reputation for its prowess in the charge and fire fight, but the Skythian infantry is underdeveloped as it is not surprising in a horse nomad society. In contrast, the shire presence of Skudata nobles in their full iron armor on iron clad horses is enough to make any enemy tremble.\n\n
Without the desire to conquer new lands the Skudata have led an arguably peaceful and isolated life disturbed only by raids into the south and internal strife. But with an ambitious ruler at the head of her army, Skudata could sweep down from the northlands and conquer all who foolishly attempted resistance.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAULS_TITLE}Mazaka
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAULS_DESCR}Difficulty: Hard\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe Mazaka known as Massagetai to the Greeks are a fearsome tribe of nomads. Raiding deep into Median territory and eastern Balkh, the Mazaka strike fear into the hearts of even the strongest men. Moving like lightning they come from the wilderness of the north to pillage and loot whatever they can find. Despite the wild differences in lifestyle the Mazaka were related to the Median and Persian Indo-Iranian family. However this blood tie is so long lost that it will not stop the searing arrows of the Mazaka from striking the heart of any Median citizen. The Median Empire lives in constant threat from these ferocious tribesmen.\n\n 
But when not on campaign in the search for booty the Massagetae can lead the peaceful life of a nomadic herdsman, following the cattle and living on the open steppes with a freedom many city dwellers only dream of. Under the command of their stern Queen Tomyris the proud warriors are both gruesome to behold in battle but also serene to witness in peace. Their territory is harsh and unforgiving, with few settlements to bring in vast amounts of money. This is what will lead any confident commander to raid the rich southern lands and supplement his people with precious treasures.\n\n
The Mazaka fight the characteristic style of steppe warfare, which makes them hard to pin down in battle and engage on the usual terms. Swift horse archers can deal terrible damage to the enemy whilst luring them further out. Once exposed, the enemy fall prey to the thunderous charge of the Mazaka noble horse. Strong spears and heavy armor make this wall of metal a fearsome sight. Whilst running rings around the enemy a good commander must remember not to get pinned down at any point.\n\n
The Mazaka stand proud in the harsh wilderness that surrounds and protects them. Would a foolish king dare risk his life in a hardy campaign against them? Or will the Mazaka rain a storm of arrows on the decadent southerners!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARMENIA_TITLE}Mada, The Median Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARMENIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Moderately Medium\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nThe people of Mada, known as Medoi (Medes) to the Greeks, came to the Iranian plateau with the Persians and thus have very strong cultural ties with them. But hundreds of years of living in a richer, more mountainous, area has made the people of Mada both strong horsemen and gave them a rich empire. Whilst Persia lived in peace during the constant wars between the ancient empires, the Median people fought many battles with the Lydians and were instrumental in the overthrow of the Assyrians.\n\n
Their vast lands are both mountainous and sun smitten, with the Caspian sea to the north they have a minor sea trade but their lands are bordered by great mountain ranges and the endless mystery of the east. The army is composed of excellent noble cavalry, organized infantry groups of archers and spearmen in masses no one could ever imagine when fully mustered.
The Lydian arch enemy in the west waits to be invaded, as it has become more rich than ever before, the city of Bâb-Ilû (Babylon as known to the Greeks) has fallen into an odd deadlock since their old King voluntarily exiled in the desert. Now or never! All you have to do first is crushing that puny rebellion in Parsa (known as Persia to the Greeks) and the back is cleared\n\n 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARTHIA_TITLE}Parsa
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARTHIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Choice\nYou can choose whether to train either your own or local troops in conquered regions\n\nIran was once invaded by two tribes; they split up into Mada (Media) in the North and (Parsa) Persia in the south. The Persians lived in peace, they were not harmed by any conflicts of war that struggled on between Mesopotamia, Palestine and Egypt. They are an Indo-European people who speak a language closely related to the language Sanskrit. It is hard for the Persians to control the regions they own, the coastline offers no harbors and the eastern regions are mountainous. The Persians served as vassal states to the Medes, who controlled the areas east of the Tigris river, but not for long.\n\n 
The founder of the Achaimenid dynasty is supposedly Hakhâmaniš, who was succeeded by many rulers seizing cities from the Elamites and slowly becoming more and more ambitious. In 559 BC, Kambujiya (Kambyses) the Elder was succeeded as king of Ansan by his son Kuruš II the Great (Kyros), But by this point Kuruš II was not yet an independent ruler. Like his predecessors before him, Kuruš had to recognize Median overlordship.\n\n   
The armies of Parsa are organized, trained soldiers with a combination of mobile cavalry, the armies under Kuruš II are the armies for the world. Hundreds of years have now past, and under an ambitious leader, King Kuruš II of Persia is about to take the step and lift this small kingdom to the first world empire, perhaps even the greatest the world will yet see. Starting a new chapter in history, which will change the world forever.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BAKTRIA_TITLE}Balkh
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BAKTRIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nThe peope of Balkh (known as Baktria to the Greeks) are a people shrouded in mystery, left out of historical documentation not much is known about these wild warriors. Related to the other Iranian tribes that settled in the Middle East, they were forced to maintain more of their steppe culture due to the harsh and more open terrain that they migrated to. They have recently lost much territory to the Medes who now hold Hegemony over much of their previous lands. This renders the peoples of Mada (Media) and Balkh as rivals in the east. However Balkh also has to deal with the Indian power of the Far East who may look toward the possessions of Balkh as a rich opportunity for conquest.\n\n
Balkh's military maintains a cavalry orientated army but they are still backed up by minor contingents of Sparabara, a practice inherited from their new territory and their rival neighbors. They are also proficient archers being able to draw on superb soldiers from Arachosia and Sogdiana. Their Baktrian horse archers are strong and swift but are not practiced to the same level as the nomads and as such an early war with the Mazaka should be avoided.\n\n
Balkh holds the key to the far east and the riches of India, should it choose to exploit this, Balkh may be able to fund a war machine capable of toppling the great empires of old and establishing the first world empire! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAGADH_TITLE}The Magadha Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAGADH_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nLocated on the very edge of the known world, the mysterious jungle realm of the Indians has grown to a great power. The mighty Šišunaga dynasty began to consolidate their realm in northern India, south of the Ganges and expands westwards. Little is known about them.\nThe Greeks say their god Dionysos had come to them teaching them how to cultivate their lands, and later their greatest mythical hero Herakles is said to have reached India as well. However, even the Persians, being much closer in proximity have not yet learned much about the Indian culture.\nThis is about to change. With the Persian Great King Darayawauš (Dareios) expanding eastwards and the Šišunaga expanding westwards, 
their empires may collide. In any case, the Persians would soon realize how dangerous the Indian military force could be.\nIndian warfare developed without much outer influences, unlike many other nations, because the difficult terrain and the natural barriers protecting the Indian subcontinent sealed them off from contact. Yet alone some sporadic nomad incursions brought a few new impulses. Nonetheless, the Indian art of war is very potent. The chief element is fire and movement. The dreaded Indian bamboo long bows have such a devastating effect that neither shield nor armor can offer much protection against them. This bow is almost omnipresent although the nobility is beginning to replace them in favour of the Nomadic composite bows. The reason is not any superiority in firepower, but simply the handling.\n
The Indian nobles, living for war and not much else, venture the dangers of battle on a light and nimble chariot driven by a trusty servant. Armed with bows they unleash their missiles on the enemy and change position. Some nobles have already begun using elephants, but still the chariot is the symbol of Indian nobility and noble warrior spirit.\nThe second most important weapon is the long sword. It is made of excellent metal and widely used after the exchange of missiles. It also has a most powerful impact when handled correctly. Since there is a warrior caste in India, most of them armed with bow and sword, this is often the case.\nIn general, due to the caste system the Indian warfare is quite professional using battle standards and music to guide their troops during the combat.\nIndian battle tactics rely 
on the effect missiles and first attack impetus of their swords to shock the enemy and scatter it’s formations. On the other hand the lack of armor or shielding makes them not only fast and maneuverable but also very vulnerable. Thus they have an enormous punch but can take only few in return and you need to stay active and dictating the battle. Otherwise, you are lost. That makes the Indian troops quite different to handle.\nOf course, the presence of battle elephants is something very special at our timeframe. It’s very useful for an Indian commander not only because of the unique availability but also because of his own weakness in horsemen, who cannot stand against any other cavalry. 


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRITONS_TITLE}The Empire of Bâb-Ilû
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRITONS_DESCR}Difficulty: Easy\nConquest Type: Choice\nYou can choose whether to train either your own or local troops in conquered regions\n\nBâb-Ilû, or Babylon as the Greeks call it, rightfully claims to be the oldest great city on earth. Indeed both people and city are most time-honoured. With a people steeped in the history of their land and a well developed culture, the inhabitants of Bâb-Ilû are a proud people led by the one and only King of Kings, the Great King. They had recently joined forces with the Mada King Uwakištar (Kyaxares) to overthrow the cruel but mighty Assyrian Empire who had been long standing rivals and enemies to Bâb-Ilû. Assuming the greater part of the Empire of Aššur the Great Kings have renewed their old ambitions of imperial domination in Mesopatamia.\n\n
On the banks of the river Euphrates the culture of the Middle East flourishes. Bâb-Ilû, city of the great gates like the blue shining Ishtar-Gate and the Hanging Gardens, is an important symbol of power and authority for king Nabu Na'id (Nabonidos). Although he has neglected the praise of Marduk in recent years, the people still praise their God’s with great fervour. The Euphrates and Tigris rivers give them a rich soil to farm, along with the well established trade routes give the inhabitants of Bâb-Ilû a flourishing economy. The army is in most aspects the direct heir of the hated oppressors from Aššur. As infamous they were, they were efficient. Professional heavy spearmen, armored archers well capable of close combat and heavy cavalry led by professional officers form the hard core, which is supplemented by light troopers levied from the lands around the city.\n\n
Holding sway over the hard-fought Levant, too, the natural enemy is the Pharaoh, despite recent policy of detente. Other possibilities are the rich Arabs or the expansion into Asia Minor, before the Lydians or Medes can do so.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PONTUS_TITLE}The Lydian Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PONTUS_DESCR}Difficulty: Easy\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nLydia in Asia Minor is the home of a warrior nation that has survived the greatest disasters one can imagine. It fought back the Kimmerian nomad horses that brought empires to ruins, they held against the Assyrians and when their time had come, they advanced forging the most powerful empire in Asia Minor seen since the Hittite Fall. The valiant warrior did not shy in front of the bronze clad hoplites, but engaged and finally overwhelmed all Greeks of Asia Minor. Likewise every other nation west of the Halys shared the same fate, yet alone Kilikia and Lykia were spared for now. Far greater lands are to conquer under the leadership of Kroisos\n\n
His wealth became proverbial as in "rich like Croesus" and this reputation is well deserved. Crops from the fields, metals from the mines and trade income from the ports provide excellent economy. It is further boosted by the world's first professional and centralized coinage. The army is no less impressive. The Lydian Lords are renowned for their skill of riding into battle with long lances, additionally a variety of light and heavy infantry, including the dreaded Hoplites, can be levied just like more cavalry, which is of good quality, too. Even better, the rich court attracts Philosophers and poets from all of Hellas increasing the glory of the King.\n\n 
What to do with this might? In the east, the arch-enemy of Lydia, the Medes, struggle with an uprising while the city of Bâb-Ilû (Babylon as known to the Greeks) has fallen into an odd deadlock since their old King voluntarily exiled in the desert. The Greeks in the west, on mainland Hellas, are friendly, especially a small but powerful state called Lakedaimon. The Pharaoh is another, greater ally of your plans. So you have free hand as your back is safe, use this wisely and you will prevail.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABA_TITLE}Saba
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Annexation\nYou can train local troops in any regions you conquer\n\nThe Arab people of Saba is a most reserved and notoriously eerie people. living in the south of Arabia they are protected by the unrelenting desert to the north. Moving amongst the environment like ghosts they befuddle any army foolish enough to enter their domain with their vast expertise on desert warfare and ambushes. With the Kushites and Rich Egypt only a hop over short waters they can mount a full invasion without fearing for the protection of their homes.\n\n
Their armies utilize the powerful and tall camels in the front line rather than in the baggage train. The distinctive smell frightens cavalry and lets Saba's camelry cut to shreds any opposing horsemen. Their fierce warriors hardened by years of scavenging and hunting in the brutal desert environment will not flee easily. And their archers can loose a devastating volley in the cruelest of desert winds. Saba is not a state to be trifled with\n\n
However the fertile lands of Arabia cannot maintain an empire for long, and if Saba has international aspirations they must seek to find new and more fertile lands. The soldiers of the desert will emerge from the fires of their harsh lives to devastate the luxurious towns of the urban civilizations. Their hearts forged in adversity will triumph over the decadence of the old empires! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Kemet, the Pharaoh's realm
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}Difficulty: Very Hard\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe civilisation of Kemet is one of the oldest and most respected in the entire world. The river Nile gives bountiful fertility to the people of Kemet letting them enjoy rich splendor and vast monuments to their own greatness. But it also supplies the men of the south with enough vigor and courage to challenge the mighty Pharaoh! The Kushites fringe upon the borders of Egypt and are a constant threat to their hegemony in eastern Africa. Not only these proud warriors threaten the Pharaoh's rule, the cunning Phoinikians and equally ancient Babylonians border their lands to the north east and all eyes are on the Gold of the Pharaoh’s treasury.\n\n
The children of the Nile have had many hundreds of years to perfect their style of warfare. Strong native spearmen with large protective shields and foreign mercenary hoplites hold the line whilst the light troopers try to decimate the enemy formations by missile fire. And to deal the killer blow the lethal chariots are employed to mince the enemy and draw them out to their deaths in the desert.\n\n
Kemet will have large amounts of gold to spend on their cities and armies, but they will also deal with threats from many sides. If the Pharaoh can master his first challenges and secure a strong foothold, then all Asia will be exposed to his mighty armies! 

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NUMIDIA_TITLE}The Kushite Kingdom
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NUMIDIA_DESCR}Difficulty: Medium\nConquest Type: Colonization\nYou can train your own troops in any regions you conquer.\n\nThe Kushites live a comparitively peaceful life compared to the rest of the world. Blessed for their long life by the Greeks, the Kushites are tall, handsome and muscular warriors steeped in the tradition of hunters. With the Pharaoh's realm Kemet right on their northern borders the Kushites have adapted to live with the occasional skirmish and raids. But the Nile flows far enough to give them sustenance and fertile ground to farm. With the vast expanse of Arabia only a short sail away the Kushites have the opportunity to either trade or make war upon the Sabaean people of the Arabian Desert.\n\n
Their resources are enough to live off and trade with the more urbanized civilizations, but if they wish to hold any world influence the Kushites must expand and bring a new age to the old empires of the world. Their military technology is far behind that of the Greeks or Iranian people, moreover they lack metal resources for the massive forging of weapons, but they had learned a lot from the professional Egyptian army. By painting their bodies with chalk and wearing the skins of lions and stallions the Kushites are a terrifying sight to behold in battle. Their heavy clubs don't need to penetrate armor to hurt an adversary and their tenacity in the melee lets them hold the line for longer than the enemy might expect.\n\n
With their roots in nature and their sights set on the riches of the north, a flood of Kushites could humble the arrogant Egyptians and press on to ravage the lands of the city dwellers. Covered in war paint, screaming a shrill paean the Kushites will strike fear into the hearts of their enemies!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARTHAGE_TITLE}Phoinikia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARTHAGE_DESCR}The Phoinikians are a people noted both for their cunning and their Navy. They have traded in every corner of the civilized world and their long sea travels have made them expert sailors. They have developed one of the first alphabets and the first to be adopted by the Greeks. But these cultural achievements do nothing to dissuade the Babylonians camping within easy striking distance of the Phoinikian cities. The Phoenicians will have to deal with both the Babylonians and the Egyptians quickly if they wish to survive and conquer fresh territory.\n\n
The military is comprised in a very similar way to the Carthaginian native troops, this being because it was a Phoinikian colony. Strong infantry and additional horse in form of heavy chariots make this army able to deal and adapt to many situations on the field. The strong navy also means naval invasions of far off and unprotected lands are a viable option for Phoinikia, and even evacuation should things turn sour with Bâb-Ilû (Babylon).\n\n
The Phoinikians are heirs to a mighty culture boasting many achievements, but it is now that the cunning worshippers of Baal must add a great empire and military dominance to their list of achievements. Phoinikia will not be alone in her rise to glory!


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SLAVE_TITLE}Autonomoi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SLAVE_DESCR}Living under no one’s rules but their own, and ready to die under their own rules if necessary!
